In this video we're going to conclude our discussion of automatic memory management
在本视频中，我们将结束对自动内存管理的讨论
with the third and last technique we're going to talk about for garbage collection
关于第三种也是最后一种技术，我们将讨论垃圾收集
called Reference Counting. So the basic idea behind reference counting is that
称为引用计数。所以引用计数背后的基本思想是
rather than waiting for memory to be completely exhausted, we're going to try
与其等待内存完全耗尽，我们将尝试
to collect an object as soon as soon as there are no more pointers to it. So as
一旦没有更多指向对象的指针，就立即收集该对象。因此，作为
soon as we discard the last pointer to an object and it becomes unreachable, we will
一旦我们丢弃指向对象的最后一个指针，并且它变得不可达，我们将
try to collect it at that point in time. And how can we do this? Well, as the name
试着在那个时间点收集它。我们怎么才能做到这一点呢？嗯，就像我的名字一样
suggests we're going to count the number of references to each object. So in each
说明我们要计算每个对象的引用次数。所以在每一种情况下
object we are going to store the number of pointers to that object. So if I have an
我们要存储指向该对象的指针数。所以如果我有一个
object in memory, and it has say, three pointers to it from other objects then
对象在内存中，它有三个指针从其他对象指向它，那么
somewhere in this object is going to be a dedicated field that contains the number
此对象中的某个位置将是包含数字的专用字段
three. And if this number ever drops to zero, if we discard these pointers and
三。如果这个数字降到零，如果我们丢弃这些指针
this number becomes a zero, then we know that nobody is pointing to this object,
这个数字变成了零，那么我们就知道没有人指向这个物体，
and it can be free. And what this means is that every assignment has to manipulate
而且它可以是免费的。这意味着每一项任务都必须操纵
the reference count in order to maintain an accurate count of the number of
引用计数，以便保持对
pointers pointing to an object. So allocating a new object, returns an object
指向对象的指针。因此分配一个新对象，会返回一个对象
with a reference count of one. So when a object is created by new it will already
引用计数为1。因此，当使用new创建对象时，它将已经
have a reference count of one. The pointer that is returned is the only reference to
引用计数为1。返回的指针是对
the object. And so we're gonna write the reference count of an object x is rc of x.
对象。所以我们要写，物体x的引用计数是x的rc。
And now when we have an assignment x gets assigned y we're going to have to update
现在，当我们有任务x被分配y时，我们将不得不更新
the reference counts of both the object that x points to and the object that y
x所指向的对象和y所指向的对象的引用计数
points to before the assignment. So, what happens here? So, if y points to p, so
指向赋值之前的。那么，这里发生了什么？所以，如果y指向p，那么
let's draw our objects here, so y is a local variable and it points to some
让我们在这里绘制我们的对象，所以y是一个局部变量，它指向一些
object p in memory, and x is also a local variable and it points to some object, o.
内存中的对象p，x也是一个局部变量，它指向某个对象o。
Okay? So now x is getting the value of y and so that's going to move this po inter
好吧?现在x得到了y的值，这将使这个po intert
from where pointer before, pointing to the same thing as y. So what's going to
从前面的位置指针，指向与y相同的东西。
happen, while p's reference count is going to go up by one, and o's reference count
发生，而p的引用计数将加1，而o的引用计数将加1
is going to go down by one. And since we decremented o's reference counts, as we
会下降一分。由于我们减少了o的引用计数，因为我们
dropped this pointer to the object o, we need to do a check to see if the reference
将此指针放到对象o中，我们需要进行检查以查看引用
count has become zero. And if the reference count has dropped to zero, then
计数已变为零。如果引用计数已降至零，则
we can free the memory for o. And then in addition to updating the reference counts
我们可以为o释放内存，然后除了更新引用计数
and checking whether the reference count of o became zero, we actually need to do
检查o的引用计数是否为零，我们实际上需要做的是
the assignment itself, alright? So every assignment, I want to stress that, every
任务本身，好吗？所以每一次作业，我想强调的是，每一次
single assignment in the program it's now translated into these four operations that
程序中的单个赋值，它现在被转换成这四个操作，
need to be done to maintain the reference counts. There are tradeoffs in reference
需要执行此操作以维护引用计数。在引用中有权衡之处
counting. It has advantages and disadvantages. One of the big advantages
开始计时了。它有优点也有缺点。最大的优势之一就是
is that it collects garbage incrementally without large pauses in the execution. So
是它以增量方式收集垃圾，而不会在执行过程中出现较大的暂停。所以
for, for kind, for applications where large pauses would be problematic, say
例如，对于长时间停顿会有问题的应用程序
real time applications or interactive applications, reference counting can
实时应用或交互式应用，引用计数可以
really help because it minimizes the length of the longest possible pause.
真的很有帮助，因为它将尽可能长的停顿时间降到最低。
Okay, so your program will never go to sleep. And just appear to stop running for
好的，所以你的程序永远不会睡着。看起来就像是不再奔跑了
some period of time because it's off collecting garbage. It always collects the
有一段时间了，因为它开始收集垃圾了。它总是收集
garbage in small incremental amounts, and so that you never see a long pause.
垃圾的增量很小，因此您永远不会看到长时间的停顿。
Reference counting, or at least a basic implementation of reference counting is
引用计数，或者至少引用计数的一个基本实现是
also quite easy to implement. It's very straight forward to go through and modify
实现起来也相当容易。它非常直截了当地通过和修改
the code to add reference counts. So you can easily imagine a code generator that
添加引用计数的代码。所以你可以很容易地想象一个代码生成器
would simply generate different code for, for the assignment operation than it
只需为赋值操作生成与它不同的代码
normally did if you were adding reference counting to an implementation. So really
如果要向实现添加引用计数，通常会这样做。所以真的
the, the changes that are needed for a simple implementation of reference
引用的简单实现所需的更改
counting to a compiler are not that pervasive. Now there are some
对编译器进行计数并不是那么普遍。现在有一些
disadvantages , to reference counting. One, is that manipulating the reference
缺点，以供参考计数。其一，就是操纵参照物
counts at each assignment is really quite slow. So, if you remember what happens, we
每次作业的点数都很慢。所以，如果你还记得发生了什么，我们
have a couple of updates to reference counts, so we have to update, you know,
有几个引用计数的更新，所以我们必须更新，你知道，
the reference count of two objects. To do an assignment. This is, this is the code
两个对象的引用计数。去做一项任务。这是，这是代码
to do an assignment and then we have an if statement. And then we actually, do the
来做一个作业，然后我们有一个if语句。然后我们实际上做的是
assignment itself. So there's two reference count updates that's has to see
任务本身。因此有两个引用计数更新需要查看
if our reference count became zero and then we actually do the assignment. So the
如果我们的引用计数为零，那么我们实际上就完成了任务。因此，
overhead here is substantial. You're taking every single assignment, in the
这里的开销很大。你接受了每一项任务，在
program and blowing up its cost by at least four or five times. And that will
计划，并使其成本至少增加四五倍。而那将会
have a very noticeable impact on the performance of many programs. Now it is
对许多程序的性能有非常明显的影响。现在是了
possible to optimize reference counting. So for example, if we had two updates to
可以优化引用计数。例如，如果我们有两次更新
the same object, say within a basic block or even within a control flow graph, a
相同对象，比如在基本挡路内，甚至在控制流图内，
compiler, a smart optimizing compiler, could frequently combine those reference
编译器是一种智能优化编译器，可以频繁地将这些引用组合在一起
count operations together. So instead of updating the reference count to the object
一起计算操作数。因此，不是更新对象的引用计数
two times, it can just update it one time. And, similarly if there were even more
两次，它只能更新一次。同样，如果有更多
reference count updates, potentially all of those could be coalesced within some
引用计数更新，可能所有这些都可以合并到一些
region of the program. The problem with that, is that is becomes very tricky to
程序的区域。这样做的问题是，这变得非常棘手
get that right. So a, a simple implementation of reference counting is
做好这件事。因此，引用计数的一个简单实现是
quite slow. But easy to get right. A very sophisticated implementation of reference
相当慢。但是很容易做对。引用的一个非常复杂的实现
counting or highly optimized implementation of reference counting, is
计数或引用计数的高度优化实现，是
somewhat faster. Still has a noticeable performance impact if you're reference
稍微快一点。仍然对性能有明显的影响，如果您引用
counting all objects but it is substantially faster. However, it's quite
对所有物体进行计数，但速度要快得多。然而，它是相当的
tricky to get it correct. The other problem with reference counting is that it
要把它弄对是很棘手的。引用计数的另一个问题是它
cannot directly collect circular structures. So to see this let's draw, a
不能直接收集环形结构。为了看到这一点，让我们画一个
little heap with a circular structure. And so let's say we have a local variable x
具有圆形结构的小堆。假设我们有一个局部变量x
and it points to some object in t he heap. And that object has a pointer to another
它指向堆中的某个对象。并且该对象具有指向另一个对象的指针
object, alright? And that object, that second object then has a pointer back to
反对，好吗？然后，第二个对象会有一个指针返回到
the first object. Okay so here x is pointing to say a circularly length list
第一个对象。好的，这里x指向的是一个循环长度列表
of length two, alright? And if we add in the reference counts here, what would
第二段，好吗？如果我们在这里加上引用计数，会有什么
those look like? Well, this object down here the second object here actually one
那些看起来像什么？这里的这个物体这里的第二个物体实际上是
reference to it so its reference count will be one. And this first object has two
引用它，因此它的引用计数将为1。第一个对象有两个
pointers to it, one from x and one from the other object and so its reference
指向它的指针，一个来自x，一个来自另一个对象，因此它的引用
count is two. Okay, so here is our little heap and we can see that there is no
数到二。好的，这是我们的小堆，我们可以看到没有
garbage here because all the objects are reachable from a, a local variable or
此处为垃圾，因为所有对象都可以从、局部变量或
variable of the program. Now if we were to assign a new value to x, lets say that we
程序的变量。现在，如果我们给x赋一个新值，假设我们
have the assignment x gets null. Alright, so this pointer goes away. But what's
使赋值x为空。好的，那么这个指针就消失了。但是什么是
going to happen? Well when we do that assignment, we're going to change the
会发生吗？当我们完成这项任务时，我们要改变
reference count here of this object, it's now gonna be one. And if we look at this
这个对象的引用计数，现在它将是1。如果我们看看这个
heap we now see that these objects, these two objects are unreachable. Okay, so
堆，我们现在看到这些对象，这两个对象是不可达的。好的，那么
these are unreachable. But notice that the reference counts are not zero, so we can't
这些是遥不可及的。但是请注意，引用计数不是零，所以我们不能
collect them. The garbage collector or the reference counting implementation, will
把它们收起来。垃圾收集器或引用计数实现将
check the reference counts and see oh, these are one and so we can't delete them.
检查引用计数，发现哦，这些是1，所以我们不能删除它们。
And then, what it can't see is that the only references to these objects are from
然后，它看不到的是对这些对象的唯一引用来自
other, unreachable objects. So, the bottom line is that reference counting can't
其他无法到达的对象。所以，底线是引用计数不能
collect circular structures and there is only really two ways to deal with that.
收集圆形结构，实际上只有两种方法来处理。
One is if the programmer remembers whenever a circular structure is going to
其一是程序员是否记得循环结构何时要
become unreadable, to somehow break the circularity. So for example, before we
变得不可读，以某种方式打破循环。举个例子，在我们
clobbered the pointer to x here, we remembered to go in and say set, you know,
把指针指向这里的x，我们记得进去说SET，你知道，
this pointer here to null. If we nulled out one of the pointers in this cycle, so
这里的指针指向NULL。如果我们清除了这个循环中的一个指针，那么
that there was no longer a cycle, then the reference counting would work correctly
如果不再有循环，则引用计数将正常工作
because then the reference count of this object would go to zero when, when this
因为这样，这个对象的引用计数就会变成零，当这个
pointer was dropped from x and that would cause the reference count of this object
指针已从x中删除，这将导致此对象的引用计数
also to go to zero after this object was deleted, okay? The other possibility is to
也要在这个对象被删除后归零，好吗？另一种可能性是
back reference counting by some other garbage collection technique that can
通过某些其他垃圾收集技术进行反向引用计数，这些垃圾收集技术可以
collect cycles. And so, in some reference counting systems for example most of the
收集周期。因此，在一些引用计数系统中，例如大多数
garbage collection is done by reference counting but every now and again, once in
垃圾收集是通过引用计数来完成的，但是每隔一段时间，在
a very, very while, you might want to mark and sweep collector to go through and
在很长一段时间内，您可能需要标记和清扫收集器
clean out any circular but unreachable data structures.
清除所有循环但无法访问的数据结构。